最后，我们来讨论两个姿势之间的插值问题。姿势有翻译
Finally, we come to the problem of interpolating between two poses. Poses have got a translational
和旋转部件。我们需要单独插入它们。我们称之为笛卡儿
and a rotational component. We need to interpolate them separately. We refer to this as Cartesian
插值。让我们考虑两个姿势;姿势0和姿势1，每个都可以表示
interpolation. Let’s consider two poses; pose 0 and pose 1, each can be represented
通过旋转矩阵和向量。我们可以将每个姿势的旋转矩阵转换为
by a rotation matrix and a vector. We can convert the rotation matrix of each pose into
一个唯一的四元数，我们可以使用线性插值插值平移
a unique quaternion and we can interpolate the translation using the linear interpolation
我们之前介绍过的公式。S是时间的函数，从0到0平滑变化
formula that we introduced earlier. S is a function of time, varies smoothly from 0 to
1在轨迹的持续时间内。并且，我们使用四元数插入旋转
1 over the duration of the trajectory. And, we interpolate the rotation using the quaternion
我们在上一节介绍的插值公式。如果我们想要，我们可以转换
interpolation formula that we introduced in the last section. If we want, we can convert
插值四元数返回旋转矩阵，将其与插值平移相结合
the interpolated quaternion back to a rotation matrix, combine it with the interpolated translation
并重建一个齐次变换矩阵。现在让我们在两个姿势之间进行插值
and rebuild a homogeneous transformation matrix. Let’s now interpolate between two poses
以均匀变换矩阵的形式描述。第一个姿势是空姿势。它
described in terms of homogeneous transformation matrices. The first pose is a null pose. It
只有0个方向，平移分量为0.第二个姿势有限
just got 0 orientation and a translational component of 0. The second pose has a finite
平移分量和有限旋转分量由这种均匀定义
translational component and a finite rotational component and is defined by this homogeneous
转换矩阵在这里。现在，我可以在这两个姿势之间创建一个平滑的轨迹
transformation matrix here. Now, I can create a smooth trajectory between these two poses
使用工具箱功能，ctraj代表笛卡尔轨迹。而且，争论
using the Toolbox function, ctraj which stands for Cartesian trajectory. And, the arguments
是最初的姿势，最终的姿势和时间步数。结果是一个矩阵
are the initial pose, the final pose and the number of time steps. The result is a matrix
那是4x4x50.再一次，这是一堆均匀变换矩阵。
that’s 4 x 4 x 50. Once again, this is a stack of homogeneous transformation matrices.
堆栈中的第一个元素，查看所有行和所有列以及第一个
The first element in the stack, look at all the rows and all the columns and the first
在堆栈中看起来像这样。但是，堆栈中的第10个，看看所有的行和
in the stack looks like this. But, the 10th one in the stack, look at all the rows and
所有列和堆栈中的第10列都是这样的。
all the columns and the 10th in the stack looks like this.
该堆叠中的每个均匀变换表示沿轨迹和姿势的姿势
Each homogeneous transformation in this stack represents a pose along a trajectory and pose
沿着这条轨道平稳地变化，在平移方面顺利而且顺畅
varies smoothly along this trajectory, smoothly in terms of translation and smoothly in terms
方向。我可以使用tranimate函数绘制这个，我们在这里看到了
of orientation. I can plot this using the tranimate function and we see here that the
姿势正在从位置和方向平滑地从初始姿势变为最终姿势。
pose is changing from the initial pose to the final pose smoothly in position and in orientation.